{"test_questions": [[{"question": "Statements: No women teacher can play. Some women teachers are athletes.\nConclusions:\n\nMale athletes can play.\nSome athletes can play.", "opta": "Only conclusion I follows", "optb": "Only conclusion II follows", "optc": "Either I or II follows", "optd": "Neither I nor II follows", "opte": "Both I and II follow", "ans": "D", "explanation": "Since one premise is negative, the conclusion must be negative. So, neither conclusion follows.\nRead: Important Rules and Formulas for Logical Deduction."}, {"question": "Statements: All bags are cakes. All lamps are cakes.\nConclusions:\n\nSome lamps are bags.\nNo lamp is bag.", "opta": "Only conclusion I follows", "optb": "Only conclusion II follows", "optc": "Either I or II follows", "optd": "Neither I nor II follows", "opte": "Both I and II follow", "ans": "C", "explanation": "Since the middle term 'cakes' is not distributed even once in the premises, no definite conclusion follows. However, I and II involve only the extreme terms and form a complementary pair. So, either I or II follows."}, {"question": "Statements: All mangoes are golden in colour. No golden-coloured things are cheap.\nConclusions:\n\nAll mangoes are cheap.\nGolden-coloured mangoes are not cheap.", "opta": "Only conclusion I follows", "optb": "Only conclusion II follows", "optc": "Either I or II follows", "optd": "Neither I nor II follows", "opte": "Both I and II follow", "ans": "B", "explanation": "Clearly, the conclusion must be universal negative and should not contain the middle term. So, it follows that 'No mango is cheap'. Since all mangoes are golden in colour, we may substitute 'mangoes' with 'golden-coloured mangoes'. Thus, II follows."}, {"question": "Statements: Some kings are queens. All queens are beautiful.\nConclusions:\n\nAll kings are beautiful.\nAll queens are kings.", "opta": "Only conclusion I follows", "optb": "Only conclusion II follows", "optc": "Either I or II follows", "optd": "Neither I nor II follows", "opte": "Both I and II follow", "ans": "D", "explanation": "Since one premise is particular, the conclusion must be particular. So, neither I nor II follows."}, {"question": "Statements: Some doctors are fools. Some fools are rich.\nConclusions:\n\nSome doctors are rich\nSome rich are doctors.", "opta": "Only conclusion I follows", "optb": "Only conclusion II follows", "optc": "Either I or II follows", "optd": "Neither I nor II follows", "opte": "Both I and II follow", "ans": "D", "explanation": "Since both the premises are particular, no definite conclusion follows."}, {"question": "Statements: All roads are waters. Some waters are boats.\nConclusions:\n\nSome boats are roads.\nAll waters are boats.", "opta": "Only conclusion I follows", "optb": "Only conclusion II follows", "optc": "Either I or II follows", "optd": "Neither I nor II follows", "opte": "Both I and II follow", "ans": "D", "explanation": "The first premise is A type and distributes the subject. So, the middle term 'waters' which forms its predicate, is not distributed. The second premise is I type and does not distribute either subject or predicate. So, the middle term 'waters' forming its subject is not distributed. Since the middle term is not distributed even once in the premises, no definite conclusion follows."}, {"question": "Statements: No bat is ball. No ball is wicket.\nConclusions:\n\nNo bat is wicket.\nAll wickets are bats.", "opta": "Only conclusion I follows", "optb": "Only conclusion II follows", "optc": "Either I or II follows", "optd": "Neither I nor II follows", "opte": "Both I and II follow", "ans": "D", "explanation": "Since both the premises are negative, no definite conclusion follows."}, {"question": "Statements: All flowers are trees. No fruit is tree.\nConclusions:\n\nNo fruit is flower.\nSome trees are flowers.", "opta": "Only conclusion I follows", "optb": "Only conclusion II follows", "optc": "Either I or II follows", "optd": "Neither I nor II follows", "opte": "Both I and II follow", "ans": "E", "explanation": "As discussed above, the conclusion must be universal negative and should not contain the middle term. So, it follows that 'No flower is fruit'. I is the converse of this conclusion and thus it follows. II is the converse of the first premise and so it also holds."}, {"question": "Statements: Every minister is a student. Every student is inexperienced.\nConclusions:\n\nEvery minister is inexperienced.\nSome inexperienced are students.", "opta": "Only conclusion I follows", "optb": "Only conclusion II follows", "optc": "Either I or II follows", "optd": "Neither I nor II follows", "opte": "Both I and II follow", "ans": "E", "explanation": "'Every' is equivalent to 'All'. Thus, since both the premises are universal and affirmative, the conclusion must be universal affirmative and should not contain the middle term. So, I follows. II is the converse of the second premise and thus it also holds."}, {"question": "Statements: All roads are poles. No pole is a house.\nConclusions:\n\nSome roads are houses.\nSome houses are poles.", "opta": "Only conclusion I follows", "optb": "Only conclusion II follows", "optc": "Either I or II follows", "optd": "Neither I nor II follows", "opte": "Both I and II follow", "ans": "D", "explanation": "Since both the premises are universal and one premise is negative, the conclusion must be universal negative. So, neither I nor II follows."}, {"question": "Statements: All fish are tortoise. No tortoise is a crocodile.\nConclusions:\n\nNo crocodile is a fish.\nNo fish is a crocodile.", "opta": "Only conclusion I follows", "optb": "Only conclusion II follows", "optc": "Either I or II follows", "optd": "Neither I nor II follows", "opte": "Both I and II follow", "ans": "E", "explanation": "Since both the premises are universal and one premise is negative, the conclusion must be universal negative. Also, the conclusion should not contain the middle term. So, II follows; I is the converse of II and thus it also holds."}, {"question": "Statements: Some dedicated souls are angels. All social workers are angels.\nConclusions:\n\nSome dedicated souls are social workers.\nSome social workers are dedicated souls.", "opta": "Only conclusion I follows", "optb": "Only conclusion II follows", "optc": "Either I or II follows", "optd": "Neither I nor II follows", "opte": "Both I and II follow", "ans": "D", "explanation": "The first premise is an I type proposition. So, the middle term 'angels' forming the predicate is not distributed. The second premise is an A type proposition. So, the middle term 'angels' forming the predicate is not distributed. Since the middle term is not distributed even once in the premises, no definite conclusion follows."}, {"question": "Statements: No gentleman is poor. All gentlemen are rich.\nConclusions:\n\nNo poor man is rich.\nNo rich man is poor.", "opta": "Only conclusion I follows", "optb": "Only conclusion II follows", "optc": "Either I or II follows", "optd": "Neither I nor II follows", "opte": "Both I and II follow", "ans": "D", "explanation": "The first premise is an E-type proposition, So, the middle term 'gentleman' forming the subject is distributed. The second premise is an A-type proposition. So, the middle term 'gentlemen' forming the subject is distributed. Since the middle term is distributed twice, the conclusion cannot be universal. Since one premise is negative, the conclusion must be negative. Thus, it follows that 'Some rich men are not poor'. Thus, neither I nor II follows."}, {"question": "Statements: Some swords are sharp. All swords are rusty\nConclusions:\n\nSome rusty things are sharp.\nSome rusty things are not sharp.", "opta": "Only conclusion I follows", "optb": "Only conclusion II follows", "optc": "Either I or II follows", "optd": "Neither I nor II follows", "opte": "Both I and II follow", "ans": "A", "explanation": "Since one premise is particular, the conclusion must be particular and should not contain the middle term. So, I follows. Since both the premises are affirmative, the conclusion cannot be negative. Thus, II does not follow."}, {"question": "Statements: All fishes are grey in colour. Some fishes are heavy.\nConclusions:\n\nAll heavy fishes are grey in colour.\nAll light fishes are not grey in colour.", "opta": "Only conclusion I follows", "optb": "Only conclusion II follows", "optc": "Either I or II follows", "optd": "Neither I nor II follows", "opte": "Both I and II follow", "ans": "A", "explanation": "Since one premise is particular, the conclusion must be particular and should not contain the middle term. So, it follows that 'Some heavy things are grey in colour'. I is a cumulative result of this conclusion and the first premise. Thus, only I holds."}, {"question": "Statements: All good athletes win. All good athletes eat well.\nConclusions:\n\nAll those who eat well are good athletes.\nAll those who win eat well.", "opta": "Only conclusion I follows", "optb": "Only conclusion II follows", "optc": "Either I or II follows", "optd": "Neither I nor II follows", "opte": "Both I and II follow", "ans": "D", "explanation": "Since the middle term 'good athletes' is distributed twice in the premises, the conclusion must be particular and should not contain the middle term. So it follows that 'Some of those who win, eat well'."}, {"question": "Statements: All film stars are playback singers. All film directors are film stars.\nConclusions:\n\nAll film directors are playback singers.\nSome film stars are film directors.", "opta": "Only conclusion I follows", "optb": "Only conclusion II follows", "optc": "Either I or II follows", "optd": "Neither I nor II follows", "opte": "Both I and II follow", "ans": "E", "explanation": "Since both the premises are universal and affirmative, the conclusion must be universal affirmative and should not contain the middle term. So, I follows. II is the converse of the second premise and so it also holds."}, {"question": "Statements: All hill stations have a sun-set point. X is a hill station.\nConclusions:\n\nX has a sun-set point.\nPlaces other than hill stations do not have sun-set points.", "opta": "Only conclusion I follows", "optb": "Only conclusion II follows", "optc": "Either I or II follows", "optd": "Neither I nor II follows", "opte": "Both I and II follow", "ans": "A", "explanation": "Since both the premises are universal and affirmative, the conclusion must be universal affirmative and should not contain the middle term. So, only I follows."}, {"question": "Statements: Some dreams are nights. Some nights are days.\nConclusions:\n\nAll days are either nights or dreams.\nSome days are nights.", "opta": "Only conclusion I follows", "optb": "Only conclusion II follows", "optc": "Either I or II follows", "optd": "Neither I nor II follows", "opte": "Both I and II follow", "ans": "B", "explanation": "Since both the premises are particular, no definite conclusion follows. However, II is the converse of the second premise and thus it holds."}, {"question": "Statements: All jungles are tigers. Some tigers are horses.\nConclusions:\n\nSome horses are jungles.\nNo horse is jungle.", "opta": "Only conclusion I follows", "optb": "Only conclusion II follows", "optc": "Either I or II follows", "optd": "Neither I nor II follows", "opte": "Both I and II follow", "ans": "C", "explanation": "Since the middle term 'tigers' is not distributed even once in the premises, no definite conclusion follows. However, I and II involve only the extreme terms and form a complementary pair. So, either I or II follows."}, {"question": "Statements: All poles are guns. Some boats are not poles.\nConclusions:\n\nAll guns are boats.\nSome boats are not guns.", "opta": "Only conclusion I follows", "optb": "Only conclusion II follows", "optc": "Either I or II follows", "optd": "Neither I nor II follows", "opte": "Both I and II follow", "ans": "D", "explanation": "Clearly, the term 'guns' is distributed in both the conclusions without being distributed in any of the premises. So, neither conclusion follows."}, {"question": "Statements: Many scooters are trucks. All trucks are trains.\nConclusions:\n\nSome scooters are trains.\nNo truck is a scooter.", "opta": "Only conclusion I follows", "optb": "Only conclusion II follows", "optc": "Either I or II follows", "optd": "Neither I nor II follows", "opte": "Both I and II follow", "ans": "A", "explanation": "Since the first premise is particular, the conclusion must be particular and should not contain the middle term. Thus, only I follows."}, {"question": "Statements: Some papers are pens. Angle is a paper.\nConclusions:\n\nAngle is not a pen.\nAngle is a pen.", "opta": "Only conclusion I follows", "optb": "Only conclusion II follows", "optc": "Either I or II follows", "optd": "Neither I nor II follows", "opte": "Both I and II follow", "ans": "C", "explanation": "Since the middle term 'papers' is not distributed even once in the premises, no definite conclusion follows. However, I and II involve only the extreme terms and form a complementary pair. Thus, either I or II follows."}, {"question": "Statements: All birds are tall. Some tall are hens.\nConclusions:\n\nSome birds are hens.\nSome hens are tall.", "opta": "Only conclusion I follows", "optb": "Only conclusion II follows", "optc": "Either I or II follows", "optd": "Neither I nor II follows", "opte": "Both I and II follow", "ans": "B", "explanation": "Since the middle term 'tall' is not distributed even once in the premises, no definite conclusion follows. However, II is the converse of the second premise and so it holds."}, {"question": "Statements: Some papers are pens. Some pencils are pens.\nConclusions:\n\nSome pens are pencils.\nSome pens are papers.", "opta": "Only conclusion I follows", "optb": "Only conclusion II follows", "optc": "Either I or II follows", "optd": "Neither I nor II follows", "opte": "Both I and II follow", "ans": "E", "explanation": "Since both premises are particular, no definite conclusion follows. However, I is the converse of second premise, while II is the converse of the first premise. So, both of them hold."}, {"question": "Statements: Some men are educated. Educated persons prefer small families.\nConclusions:\n\nAll small families are educated.\nSome men prefer small families.", "opta": "Only conclusion I follows", "optb": "Only conclusion II follows", "optc": "Either I or II follows", "optd": "Neither I nor II follows", "opte": "Both I and II follow", "ans": "B", "explanation": "Since one premise is particular, the conclusion must be particular and should not contain the middle term. Thus, only II follows."}, {"question": "Statements: All educated people read newspapers. Rahul does not read newspaper.\nConclusions:\n\nRahul is not educated.\nReading newspaper is not essential to be educated.", "opta": "Only conclusion I follows", "optb": "Only conclusion II follows", "optc": "Either I or II follows", "optd": "Neither I nor II follows", "opte": "Both I and II follow", "ans": "A", "explanation": "Since both the premises are universal and one premise is negative, the conclusion must be universal negative and should not contain the middle term. So, only I follows."}, {"question": "Statements: All pens are chalks. All chairs are chalks.\nConclusions:\n\nSome pens are chairs.\nSome chalks are pens.", "opta": "Only conclusion I follows", "optb": "Only conclusion II follows", "optc": "Either I or II follows", "optd": "Neither I nor II follows", "opte": "Both I and II follow", "ans": "B", "explanation": "Since the middle term 'chalks' is not distributed even once in the premises, no definite conclusion follows. However, II is the converse of the first premise and so it holds."}, {"question": "Statements: Bureaucrats marry only intelligent girls. Tanya is very intelligent.\nConclusions:\n\nTanya will marry a bureaucrat.\nTanya will not marry a bureaucrat.", "opta": "Only conclusion I follows", "optb": "Only conclusion II follows", "optc": "Either I or II follows", "optd": "Neither I nor II follows", "opte": "Both I and II follow", "ans": "C", "explanation": "The data does not mention whether all intelligent girls are married to bureaucrats. So, either I or II may follow."}, {"question": "Statements: Some engineers are fools. Anand is an engineer.\nConclusions:\n\nSome fools are engineers.\nAnand is a fool.", "opta": "Only conclusion I follows", "optb": "Only conclusion II follows", "optc": "Either I or II follows", "optd": "Neither I nor II follows", "opte": "Both I and II follow", "ans": "A", "explanation": "Since the middle term 'engineer' is not distributed even once in the premises, no definite conclusion follows. However, I is the converse of the first premise and thus it holds."}, {"question": "Statements: All windows are doors. No door is wall.\nConclusions:\n\nNo window is wall.\nNo wall is door.", "opta": "Only conclusion I follows", "optb": "Only conclusion II follows", "optc": "Either I or II follows", "optd": "Neither I nor II follows", "opte": "Both I and II follow", "ans": "E", "explanation": "Since both the premises are universal and one premise is negative, the conclusion must be universal negative. Also, the conclusion should not contain the middle term. So, I follows. However, II is the converse of the second premise and thus it also holds,"}, {"question": "Statements: Most teachers are boys. Some boys are students.\nConclusions:\n\nSome students are boys.\nSome teachers are students.", "opta": "Only conclusion I follows", "optb": "Only conclusion II follows", "optc": "Either I or II follows", "optd": "Neither I nor II follows", "opte": "Both I and II follow", "ans": "A", "explanation": "Since both the premises are particular, no definite conclusion follows. However, I is the converse of the second premise and thus it holds."}, {"question": "Statements: No man is a donkey. Rahul is a man.\nConclusions:\n\nRahul is not a donkey.\nAll men are not Rahul.", "opta": "Only conclusion I follows", "optb": "Only conclusion II follows", "optc": "Either I or II follows", "optd": "Neither I nor II follows", "opte": "Both I and II follow", "ans": "A", "explanation": "Since on premise is negative, the conclusion must be negative. Conclusion II cannot follow as it contains the middle term. So, only I follows."}, {"question": "Statements: Some books are pens. No pen is pencil.\nConclusions:\n\nSome books are pencils.\nNo book is pencil.", "opta": "Only conclusion I follows", "optb": "Only conclusion II follows", "optc": "Either I or II follows", "optd": "Neither I nor II follows", "opte": "Both I and II follow", "ans": "C", "explanation": "As discussed above, the conclusion must be particular negative and should not contain the middle term. So, it follows that 'Some books are not pencils'. However, I and II involve only the extreme terms and form a complementary pair. Thus, either I or II follows."}, {"question": "Statements: All men are married. Some men are educated.\nConclusions:\n\nSome married are educated.\nSome educated are married.", "opta": "Only conclusion I follows", "optb": "Only conclusion II follows", "optc": "Either I or II follows", "optd": "Neither I nor II follows", "opte": "Both I and II follow", "ans": "E", "explanation": "Since one premise is particular, the conclusion must be particular and should not contain the middle term. So, I follows. II is the converse of I and thus it also holds."}, {"question": "Statements: All tubes are handles. All cups are handles.\nConclusions:\n\nAll cups are tubes.\nSome handles are not cups.", "opta": "Only conclusion I follows", "optb": "Only conclusion II follows", "optc": "Either I or II follows", "optd": "Neither I nor II follows", "opte": "Both I and II follow", "ans": "D", "explanation": "Both the premises are A type propositions. So, in either, the middle term 'handles' forming the predicate is not distributed. Since the middle term is not distributed even once in the premises, no definite conclusion follows"}, {"question": "Statements: No magazine is cap. All caps are cameras.\nConclusions:\n\nNo camera is magazine.\nSome cameras are magazines.", "opta": "Only conclusion I follows", "optb": "Only conclusion II follows", "optc": "Either I or II follows", "optd": "Neither I nor II follows", "opte": "Both I and II follow", "ans": "C", "explanation": "As discussed above, the conclusion must be particular negative and should not contain the middle term. So, it follows that 'Some cameras are not magazines'. However, I and II involve only the extreme terms and form a complementary pair. Thus, either I or II follows."}, {"question": "Statements: All huts are mansions. All mansions are temples.\nConclusions:\n\nSome temples are huts.\nSome temples are mansions.", "opta": "Only conclusion I follows", "optb": "Only conclusion II follows", "optc": "Either I or II follows", "optd": "Neither I nor II follows", "opte": "Both I and II follow", "ans": "E", "explanation": "As discussed above, it follows that 'All huts are temples'. I is the converse of this conclusion and so it holds. II is the converse of the second premise and so it also holds."}, {"question": "Statements: Some books are tables. Some tables are mirrors.\nConclusions:\n\nSome mirrors are books.\nNo book is mirror.", "opta": "Only conclusion I follows", "optb": "Only conclusion II follows", "optc": "Either I or II follows", "optd": "Neither I nor II follows", "opte": "Both I and II follow", "ans": "C", "explanation": "Since both the premises are particular no definite conclusion follows. However, I and II involve only the extreme terms and form a complementary pair. Thus, either I or II follows."}, {"question": "Statements: All trucks fly. Some scooters fly.\nConclusions:\n\nAll trucks are scooters.\nSome scooters do not fly.", "opta": "Only conclusion I follows", "optb": "Only conclusion II follows", "optc": "Either I or II follows", "optd": "Neither I nor II follows", "opte": "Both I and II follow", "ans": "D", "explanation": "Since the middle term 'fly' is not distributed even once in the premises, no definite conclusion follows."}, {"question": "Statements: Raman is always successful. No fool is always successful.\nConclusions:\n\nRaman is a fool.\nRaman is not a fool.", "opta": "Only conclusion I follows", "optb": "Only conclusion II follows", "optc": "Either I or II follows", "optd": "Neither I nor II follows", "opte": "Both I and II follow", "ans": "B", "explanation": "Since both the premises are universal and one premise is negative, the conclusion must be universal negative and should not contain the middle term. So, only II follows."}, {"question": "Statements: Some desks are caps. No cap is red.\nConclusions:\n\nSome caps are desks.\nNo desk is red.", "opta": "Only conclusion I follows", "optb": "Only conclusion II follows", "optc": "Either I or II follows", "optd": "Neither I nor II follows", "opte": "Both I and II follow", "ans": "A", "explanation": "Since one premise is particular and the other premise is negative, the conclusion must be particular negative and should not contain the middle term. So, it follows that 'Some desks are not red'. However, I is the converse of the first premise and thus it holds."}, {"question": "Statements: Some hens are cows. All cows are horses.\nConclusions:\n\nSome horses are hens.\nSome hens are horses.", "opta": "Only conclusion I follows", "optb": "Only conclusion II follows", "optc": "Either I or II follows", "optd": "Neither I nor II follows", "opte": "Both I and II follow", "ans": "E", "explanation": "Since one premise is particular, the conclusion must be particular and should not contain the middle term. So, II follows. I is the converse of II and so it also holds."}, {"question": "Statements: All water is divine. All temples are divine.\nConclusions:\n\nAll water is temple.\nAll temples are water.", "opta": "Only conclusion I follows", "optb": "Only conclusion II follows", "optc": "Either I or II follows", "optd": "Neither I nor II follows", "opte": "Both I and II follow", "ans": "D", "explanation": "Since the middle term 'divine' is not distributed even once in the premises, no definite conclusion can be drawn."}, {"question": "Statements: All men are dogs. All dogs are cats.\nConclusions:\n\nAll men are cats.\nAll cats are men.", "opta": "Only conclusion I follows", "optb": "Only conclusion II follows", "optc": "Either I or II follows", "optd": "Neither I nor II follows", "opte": "Both I and II follow", "ans": "A", "explanation": "Since both the premises are universal and affirmative, the conclusion must be universal affirmative. However, conclusion II, being an A-type proposition, distributes the term 'cats'. \n\nSince the term 'cats' is distributed in II without being distributed in any of the premises, so conclusion II cannot follow. Thus, only I follows."}, {"question": "Statements: All young scientists are open-minded. No open-minded men are superstitious.\nConclusions:\n\nNo scientist is superstitious.\nNo young people are superstitious.", "opta": "Only conclusion I follows", "optb": "Only conclusion II follows", "optc": "Either I or II follows", "optd": "Neither I nor II follows", "opte": "Both I and II follow", "ans": "D", "explanation": "The subject in both the conclusions is vague. The true conclusion is 'No young scientist is superstitious'. Thus, neither I nor II follows,"}, {"question": "Statements: Some pastries are toffees. All toffees are chocolates.\nConclusions:\n\nSome chocolates are toffees.\nSome toffees are not pastries.", "opta": "Only conclusion I follows", "optb": "Only conclusion II follows", "optc": "Either I or II follows", "optd": "Neither I nor II follows", "opte": "Both I and II follow", "ans": "A", "explanation": "Since one premise is particular, the conclusion must be particular and should not contain the middle term. Thus, it follows that 'Some pastries are chocolates', I is the converse of the second premise and so it holds. Since both the premises are affirmative, the conclusion cannot be negative. Thus, II does not follow."}, {"question": "Statements: All boys are honest. Sachin is honest.\nConclusions:\n\nSachin is a boy.\nAll honest persons are boys.", "opta": "Only conclusion I follows", "optb": "Only conclusion II follows", "optc": "Either I or II follows", "optd": "Neither I nor II follows", "opte": "Both I and II follow", "ans": "D", "explanation": "Both the premises are A type propositions. So, the middle term 'honest' forming the predicate in each is not distributed in either. Since the middle term is not distributed even once, no definite conclusion follows."}, {"question": "Statements: All pens are roads. All roads are houses.\nConclusions:\n\nAll houses are pens.\nSome houses are pens.", "opta": "Only conclusion I follows", "optb": "Only conclusion II follows", "optc": "Either I or II follows", "optd": "Neither I nor II follows", "opte": "Both I and II follow", "ans": "B", "explanation": "Since both the premises are universal and affirmative, the conclusion must be universal affirmative and should not contain the middle term. So, it follows that 'All pens are houses'. II is the converse of this conclusion and so it holds. Since the term 'houses' is distributed in I without being distributed in any of the premises, so I does not follow."}, {"question": "Statements: All artists are smokers. Some smokers are drunkards.\nConclusions:\n\nAll smokers are artists.\nSome drunkards are not smokers.", "opta": "Only conclusion I follows", "optb": "Only conclusion II follows", "optc": "Either I or II follows", "optd": "Neither I nor II follows", "opte": "Both I and II follow", "ans": "D", "explanation": "Since the middle term 'smokers' is not distributed even once in the premises, no definite conclusion follows."}, {"question": "Statements: All cars are cats. All fans are cats.\nConclusions:\n\nAll cars are fans\nSome fans are cars.", "opta": "Only conclusion I follows", "optb": "Only conclusion II follows", "optc": "Either I or II follows", "optd": "Neither I nor II follows", "opte": "Both I and II follow", "ans": "D", "explanation": "Since the middle term 'cats' is not distributed even once in the premises, no definite conclusion follows."}]]}